Hi, everyone! it's Ken!
皆さん、こんにちは！　Kenです！
Today, I'm heading out for some shopping.
今日は今から買い物に行きます。
I'll be walking around the city and chatting in Japanese.
街に行きます。街に行って、街を歩きながら日本語で話します。
So, let's go shopping together today!
今日は皆さんと一緒に買い物に行きます。
It takes about an hour by train to get to the city from here.
ここから街まで電車で１時間ぐらいかかります。
Today, I’m going to Taipei.
今日は台北の街に行きます。
Since I live in Taiwan now, I’ve been making a lot of videos about Taiwan lately.
今、僕は台湾に住んでいるので、最近は台湾の動画が多いですね。
There are so many beautiful places in Taiwan.
台湾もきれいな場所がたくさんあります。
Oh, but in 2025, this year, I plan to go back to Japan for a short stay.
あ、でも、今年２０２５年、僕は日本に帰るつもりです。
When I visit Japan for trips, I’ll make a lot of videos there too.
まぁ、旅行で日本に帰ったら、日本の動画もたくさん撮ります。
Please look forward to the Japan videos!
日本の動画も楽しみにしていてくださいね！
Alright, so first, I’ll take the train.
じゃあ、え～と、まずは電車に乗ります。
It’s about a 10-minute walk to the station from here.
ここから歩いて１０分ぐらいですね。電車の駅があります。
Let’s head to the station first!
まずは電車の駅にいきましょう！
I’m getting on the train now.
今から電車に乗ります。
I just got off the train.
今、駅を出たところです。
It did take about an hour by train, as expected.
やっぱり電車で１時間ぐらいかかりました。
So, this is the center of Taipei.
え～と、ここは台北の中心です。
There are so many people around.
たくさん人がいます。
There are lots of shops in this area.
この辺にたくさんお店があります。
Most of the shops around here are pretty high-end.
この辺のお店は結構高級なお店が多いです。
They sell designer bags and accessories,
ブランドの鞄とかアクセサリーとか、
that kind of stuff.
そういうお店がたくさんあります。
Not really my thing, but I’ll show you around a bit.
あんまり僕に関係ないお店ですね。ちょっと街の様子を見せますね。
Can you see? It looks like this.
見えますか？こんな感じです。
I’ve been here before.
僕はこの辺に来たことがあります。
I think I’ve visited this area about twice.
たぶん、２回ぐらい来たことがあります。
But it wasn’t for shopping.
それは買い物のために来たんじゃなくて、
I came to see a famous building.
有名な建物を見に来ました。
We’ll get to see that building later, so let’s check it out together.
あとでその建物も見えるので、一緒に見に行きましょう！
This is one of the newer areas in Taipei.
ここは台北の中でも新しい場所です。
The buildings are new, and the streets are really clean.
建物も新しいし、道もきれいです。
And yeah, a lot of the people walking around here are pretty fashionable.
まぁ、歩いている人も結構おしゃれな人が多いです。
Christmas just ended recently.
この前クリスマスは終わりました。
Even though Christmas is over,
クリスマス終わったんですけど、
the lights are still up.
なんか、まだイルミネーションがあります。
They’re beautiful, aren’t they? Like this. Super pretty!
きれいですよね！ こんな感じ。すごいきれいです！
Do you guys like shopping?
皆さんは買い物が好きですか？
Today, I came here to do some shopping.
今日僕は買い物に来ました。
I came to buy something.
買い物をしに来ました。
What I’m buying today is a computer.
今日僕が買うものはパソコンです。
I already have a laptop and
僕はノートパソコンと
a tiny mini PC, like a small desktop computer.
小さい小さいミニPCっていうデスクトップパソコンがあります。
But that
でも、その
small mini PC, the one like a desktop, broke.
デスクトップパソコンみたいな小さいミニPCが壊れました。
Since it’s broken, I’ve been looking for a new computer recently.
壊れちゃったので、最近新しいパソコンを探していました。
And today, I’m going to buy a new computer.
今日はその新しいパソコンを買いに行きます。
Actually, I already bought it.
実はもう買いました。
I looked it up online and paid with my credit card.
オンラインで探して、クレジットカードで支払いしました。
But when I bought it, it was still just a pre-order.
でも僕がそのパソコンを買った時、まだ予約だけ。予約だけでした。
The store didn’t have it in stock.
お店に在庫がなかったです。
So today, I’m heading out to pick up the computer.
なので今日は今からそのパソコンを受け取りに行きます。
Uh, wait a second. I’m not sure which direction to go.
え～と、ちょっと待ってくださいね。方向が分かりません。
Was it this way? Or that way? I’m not really familiar with this area,
あっちだっけ？あっちだっけ？僕はあんまりこの辺に詳しくないので、
so let me stop and check Google Maps. Hold on a sec.
ちょっと止まって、グーグルマップを見ます。ちょっと待ってください。
Alright, I just checked Google Maps.
今グーグルマップを見ました。
According to Google Maps,
グーグルマップによると、
the store I’m heading to is straight ahead from here.
僕が今から行くお店はここをまっすぐ行くそうです。
It should be there if I just keep going straight.
まっすぐ行ったら、あるそうです。
So yeah, I’m on my way now to pick up the computer I bought.
まぁ今から僕は買ったパソコンを受け取りに行くんですけど、
Do you guys use computers for work?
皆さんは仕事の時にパソコンを使いますか？
Or even if it’s not for work, when you’re at home,
仕事じゃなくても、家で時間を過ごす時、
for example,
例えば
do you watch movies or YouTube on your computer?
パソコンで映画を見たりYouTubeを見たりしますか？
I use my computer every day.
僕は毎日パソコンを使います。
I use my computer every day for work.
仕事で毎日パソコンを使います。
So if my computer breaks, it’s a bit of a hassle.
なので、パソコンが壊れたら、ちょっと大変です。
For me, it’s kind of a big deal.
僕にとって、ちょっと大変です。
What have you guys bought recently?
最近、皆さんは何を買いましたか？
Actually, you know, the computer that broke—I bought it about a year ago.
実はね、あの～、僕のちょっと壊れたパソコン、１年前ぐらいに買いました。
I only bought it a year ago!
１年前に買ったばかりですよ！
But it was really cheap, so I guess it can’t be helped.
でもそのパソコンはすごく安かったから、しょうがないですね。
Yeah, no surprise it broke.
壊れてもしょうがないです。
What kind of computer do you guys use?
皆さんパソコンある人はどんなパソコンを使ってますか？
Can you guess what kind of computer I bought?
僕が買ったパソコンなんだと思いますか？
It’s a super famous computer.
めっちゃ有名なパソコンです。
There’s an apple logo on it.
パソコンにりんごのマークがあります。
Yep, I bought an Apple Mac mini.
そう、AppleのMac miniっていうパソコンを買いました。
So now I’m heading to the Apple Store.
なので、今からApple Storeに行きます。
Actually, up until now, I’ve only ever used Windows computers.
実は僕今までwindowsのパソコンしか使わなかったです。
The computers I have now are also Windows ones.
今持っているパソコンもwindowsのパソコンですね。
A long time ago, when I was in high school...
あの～、昔昔、僕が高校生だった時、
I used a smartphone called iPhone 4S.
iPhone４Sっていうスマホを使っていました。
Do you guys remember iPhone 4S? That was about 13 years ago?
皆さん覚えてますか？iPhone４S。１３年前ぐらいかな。
I was in high school back then, so...
僕は その時 高校生だったので、
all I needed my phone to do was make calls, send emails, and use social media with friends.
スマホで電話とメールと、友達とSNSをするぐらいでした。
That was good enough for me.
まぁ、それができればOKでした。
So yeah, 12 or 13 years ago...
なので１２年、１３年前、
I don’t even remember if I liked the iPhone or not.
僕はiPhoneが好きだったかどうか全然覚えていません。
I used the iPhone for about three or four years.
iPhoneを３年４年ぐらい使いました。
Then, after my iPhone 4S broke...
で、その後、iPhone４Sが壊れた後、
I bought an Android phone.
androidのスマホを買いました。
And ever since then, I’ve been using Android phones.
で、それからずっとスマホはandroidを使ってます。
Do you guys use Apple products like MacBooks or iPhones?
皆さんはAppleのMacbookとかiPhoneとか使ってますか?
Oh, look, there are some illuminations here too.
あ、ここも なんか イルミネーションがあります。
The trees are all lit up.
木に電気がついています。
Illuminations! Oh, let’s go check that out!
イルミネーション。あ、ちょっとあっちに行きましょう！
Excuse me!
すいません！
I came here to shop, but...
買い物に来たんですけど、
This area is so stylish. Can you see it?
この辺はすごくおしゃれなので...。見えますか？
This place is pretty stylish, isn’t it?
このお店おしゃれですよね。
Right now, I’m filming while checking out the shops here.
今、僕は動画を撮りながら、お店とかも見ています。
Wow, this place is really a city. A big one.
いや～、ここは本当に街ですね。大きい街です。
And the buildings here are super tall!
なんか、建物がめちゃめちゃ高い！
I grew up in the countryside, so I’m not used to places like this.
僕は田舎出身なので、こういうところは慣れてないです。
What about you guys? Do you like big cities like this?
皆さんはどうですか？こういう大きい街が好きですか？
I don’t usually go to big cities just to shop, but...
僕はあんまり買い物のために都会に行くっていうことはないんですけど、
How about you?
皆さんはどうですか？
When I need something or want something...
僕はなんかほしいものとか必要なものがある時、
I try to buy it online as much as possible.
できるだけオンラインで買うようにしています。
When you buy online...
オンラインで買ったら、
the delivery person brings it right to your door, doesn’t he?
宅急便の人が自分の家まで届けてくれるじゃないですか。
That service is amazing!
あのサービスすごいですよね！
It’s super convenient. Oh, hang on a second.
めっちゃ便利です。ちょっと待ってください。
I got lost again.
また道が分からなくなっちゃいました。
Let me check Google Maps real quick.
ちょっとグーグルマップを見ます。
We’re almost there!
もうすぐ着きます！
There is a really famous building in Taiwan over there.
あそこに台湾のめっちゃ有名な建物があります。
Let’s check it out together!
ちょっと一緒に見ましょう！
Can you see it? That building!
見えますか？　あの建物！
Whoa, it’s so tall! It’s called Taipei 101.
うわ！めっちゃ高い！　名前は台北１０１って言います。
That’s its Japanese name.
それは日本語の名前ですね。
Taipei 101. It’s the tallest building in Taiwan.
台北１０１。あの建物は台湾で一番高い建物です。
It’s 508 meters (1,667 ft) tall. Wow, that’s really high!
高さは５０８ｍ。うわぁ、めっちゃ高いですね！
It’s incredible! So impressive!
すごい！ すごいですよ！ めっちゃ迫力があります！
How tall is the tallest building or tower in your country?
皆さんの国の１番高い建物とか１番高いタワー何ｍぐらいですか?
Wow, this is amazing!
うわぁ、これはすごい！
I’ve been to this area before.
僕は昔 この辺に来たことがあります。
So, I’ve seen this building before.
なので、この建物を 昔 見たことがあります。
But no matter how many times I see it, it’s still impressive!
おお！　でも、何回見てもすごいですね！
Inside this building...
この建物の中に、
there are shops, restaurants, and an observation deck, apparently.
お店とかレストランとか展望台とかがあるらしいです。
I guess the observation deck is up at the top.
展望台はどこかな。まぁ、上の方ですね。
I’ve never been inside that building.
僕はあの建物に入ったことはないです。
That building.
あの建物。
Actually, I’ve never gone inside it.
実は僕はあの建物に入ったことがないです。
But someday, I’d like to check it out.
でも、いつか入ってみたいです。
Today, though, I’m not going to Taipei 101.
今日はね、台北１０１に行くんじゃなくて、
I’m heading to the Apple Store.
Apple Store に行きます。
I heard that the Apple Store is next to Taipei 101.
で、Apple Storeは台北１０１の隣にあるそうです。
That’s what my wife told me.
まぁ、僕の妻から聞きました。
Um, I think it’s over there. Probably over there.
えっと、あっちかな。たぶん、あっちですね。
Oh, there it is! I’m going to pick up my computer now. Just a second!
はい、ありました！ 今からパソコンを受け取ってきます。ちょっと待っててくださいね。
Alright, I just got my computer!
はい、今パソコンを受け取りました！
Wow, I’m so excited!
わあ！　楽しみ！
I can’t wait to open it when I get home!
これを家に帰って開けるのがめっちゃ楽しみです！
It’s evening now. After picking up this computer,
今、夜ですね。このパソコンを受け取った後、
I ended up looking at iPhones, MacBooks, and other products.
ついでにiPhoneとかmacbookとか他の商品を見ました。
I checked out some other stuff too, and before I knew it, it got dark.
ついでに他の商品も見ました。そしたら、夜になっちゃいました。
It’s around 6 PM now.
今、夜６時ぐらいかな。
Almost 7 PM.
もうすぐ夜７時です。
I’m heading home now to unbox this computer!
今から家に帰って、このパソコンを開けようと思います！
I’m home!
ただいま！
Alright, let’s unbox this together!
じゃあ今から皆さんと一緒にこれを開けていきたいと思います！
This is my work desk.
ここは僕の仕事の机です。
I usually teach Japanese lessons here
僕はいつもここで日本語のレッスンをしたり、
and edit YouTube videos.
YouTubeの動画を編集したりしています。
Oh, this desk is awesome!
あ、この机すごいですよ！
When you press this button, it moves up automatically.
ボタンを押すと、自動で上がります。
Isn’t it cool?
すごいでしょ！
Out of everything I bought last year, I’m happiest with this.
これは僕が去年買ったものの中で、１番満足しています。
Last year was 2024.
去年２０２４年ですね。
This might end up being my best purchase of 2025.
で、これ、２０２５年の中で１番いい買い物になったかな。
Well, 2025 has just started, though.
まぁ２０２５年はまだ始まったばかりですけどね。
Alright, let’s open this box now!
はい、じゃあ、今からこの箱を開けたいと思います！
How do I even open this?
どうやって開けるんですかね？
Maybe here? Ah, yeah, that’s it.
たぶん、ここ。あ～、そうですね。
I pull here to open it. And then pull this side too.
ここを引っ張って開けます。こっちも引っ張って開けます。
Then flip it over, and... wow! Nice!
で、反対にして、はい。おお！　いいね！
It looks super beautiful!
すごいめっちゃきれいです！
Wow, looks great!
へえ！　いい感じ！
Apple’s designs are simple and nice! So cute!
Appleのデザインはシンプルでいいですね！可愛いです！
It’s really small and cute!
すごい小さくて可愛いです！
And here’s the power cable inside.
あとは中に電源コードが入ってますね。
I’m not sure how to open this power cord packaging.
電源の線、これどうやってあけるかわかりません。
What is this? What’s this for?
何これ？ これは何ですか？
Oh, it’s the Mac mini manual! This is the manual.
Mac mini 、あ！ 説明書！　これは説明書ですね。
Since I went ahead and bought this, in 2025,
これ、せっかく買ったので、今年２０２５年、
I plan to use this computer
このパソコンを使って、
to make lots of YouTube videos!
たくさんYouTubeの動画を作りたいと思います！
Please look forward to my YouTube videos this year too!
皆さん今年も僕のYouTubeの動画 楽しみにしていてください！
Have you guys bought anything recently?
皆さんは最近何か買い物をしましたか？
If there’s something you bought recently that you’re happy with, let me know in the comments!
皆さんが最近買って良かったもの、是非コメント欄で教えてください！
Alright, see you in the next video!
じゃあ、また次の動画で会いましょう！
Bye!
またね！